A road(?) ....................
Gilgamish ...................
in the plain ..................
his hair growing thickly like the corn.
He came forth ...
into his presence.
They met in the wide park of the land.
Enkidu held fast the door
with his foot,
and permitted not Gilgamish to enter.
They grappled with each other
goring like an ox.
The threshold they destroyed.
The wall they demolished.
Gilgamish and Enkidu
grappled with each other,
goring like an ox.
The threshold they destroyed.
The wall they demolished.
Gilgamish bowed
to the ground at his feet
and his javelin reposed.
He turned back his breast.
After he had turned back his breast,
Enkidu unto that one
spoke, even unto Gilgamish.
“Even as one did thy mother
bear thee,
she the wild cow of the cattle stalls,
Ninsunna,
whose head she exalted more than a husband.
Royal power over the people
Enlil has decreed for thee.”